

#### **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

🚺 Arsen Tabaku

Karl-Theodor-Strasse 75, 80803, Munich (Germany)

arsentabaku2@gmail.com

+49 (0)176 66979019

Sex Male | Date of birth 03/06/1997 | Nationality Albanian

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Full-stack software engineer, currently working at VRdirect GmbH. Ability to work hard and learn quickly, often in high-pressure situations, in order to fully understand a new product, platform, or any mixture of the two. Experienced in object-oriented programming and keen to solve real life problems by using the power of software engineering principles. Strong troubleshooting and problem solving skills with an analytical mindset and logical thinking.

#### **EDUCATION**

15/10/2018-30/09/2020	Master degree in Media Computer Science
	Saarland University - Saarbrücken (Germany)
22/10/2015–19/07/2018	Bachelor degree in Information and Communication Technology (ICT) University of Tirana - Tirana (Albania)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

01/10/2020 - Present (Full-time)

## Full-stack Software Engineer at VRdirect GmbH – Munich (Germany)

- Developing features in multiple softwares (web, mobile, desktop).
- Enhancing products quality assurance by developing tests (unit, e2e).
- Supporting the improvement of software architecture.

01/01/2020 – 30/09/2020 (Full-time)

#### Master thesis at Cluster of Excellence, HCI lab - Saarbrücken (Germany)

- Conceptualized physics-based metaphors based on users pre-existing knowledge to provide more intuitive and natural interactions.
- Implemented the metaphors in a VR application.
- Conducted a user study to validate the raised hypotheses.

01/03/2020 - 30/09/2020 (Part-time)

# Software Developer at ZeMA - Saarbrücken (Germany)

• Developed a VR application to (dis)assemble complex 3D models where employees can practice before using them in the real world.

09/09/2019 - 07/02/2020 (Internship)

## Software Developer at DHfPG - Saarbrücken (Germany)

- Developed a platform to easily create virtual tours.
- Created an interactive virtual tour for a gym where fitness instructors can navigate through to help the customers that need assistance.
- Conducted a user study to validate the raised hypotheses.

01/07/2018 - 15/06/2019 (Part-time)

# **Coding Mentor at TiranaIT - Tirana (Albania)**

 Tutoring university students subjects like IT basics, Algorithmics and Data Structures and Web programming.

#### **BEST PROJECTS**

09/2019 – 02/2020	Developed a VR coaching tool for educating fitness trainers which simulates pre-recorded 3D-environments of a gym in VR where users can navigate to spot customers that need help and answer questions asked within VR.
04/2019 – 07/2019	Developed a Smart Mirror project for HKBSaar and DFKI which detects peoples' faces and augments those by adding hairstyles, hair colors, beards, glasses etc.
04/2019 – 08/2019	Developed a boxing game in VR using my own 3D character. Apart from the game itself, this project had a great focus on having as good UX as possible.
09/2018 – 12/2018	Developed a library management system which tends to manage specific problems faced on libraries such as managing actual members and adding new ones, storing and accessing the books and having the option to chase them when loaned.
01/2018 - 04/2018	Developed a desktop app which facilitates the way how busy people and businesses maintain their schedule.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming (Angular, Javascript, Typescript, NextJs, RxJS, NodeJs, NativeScript, Ionic, Electron, Java)
- Automation testing (Cypress, Appium, Cucumber, Jest, Jasmine, Mocha, JUnit, Browserstack)
- Databases (MongoDB, SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL)
- APIs (REST APIs, Swagger, Postman)
- Authentication (OAuth 2.0, OpenID Connect, Auth0)
- CSS frameworks (Bootstrap, Materialize, Material Design, Angular Material, PrimeNg)
- Modern Development Tools (Jira, Confluence, SourceTree, Git, Github, Bitbucket)
- Software Project Management (SDLC, Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, UML/Sequence/Flow diagrams)
- Software Engineering Principles (Clean Code, SOLID, YAGNI, KISS)
- DevOps (CI/CD, Azure DevOps, Docker, Yaml, Bash)
- Operating Systems (MacOS, Windows, Linux)
- IDEs (VS Code, Atom, Sublime, Visual Studio)
- Documentation (Draw.io, UML Diagrams, Zeplin, Latex, Prezi, MS Office, Google package)
- Digital Image Processing (Photoshop CC, Lightroom, Canva, Fotor, Inkscape)
- 3D Modeling & Animation (Storyboarding, Blender, MasterPieceVR, Mixamo)

#### LINGUISTIC PROFICIENCY

	Listening	Reading	Speaking	Writing
Albanian	Native	Native	Native	Native
English	C1	C1	C1	C1
German	B1	B1	B1	B1
Italian	B1	B1	A2	A2
Spanish	B1	A2	A2	A2

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Communication Quick learning Hard working Problem solving Critical thinking Work ethic